Ayomide Ibosiola

Talent Acquisition Specialist

enochibosiola@gmail.com +2348099691225 100271 Ikeja, Lagos

https://ayomideibosiola.netlify.app,https://calendly.com/ayomideibosiola

in https://linkedin.com/in/ayomide-ibosiola

Summary

Data-driven Talent Acquisition Specialist, capable of Advanced Boolean Search to identify and mine top candidates with a strong Software Development background, specializing in building web and mobile applications that are aesthetically pleasing and logic-driven.

There's nothing like the thrill of a candidate's enthusiastic "Yes!" to an offer and an equally pleased Hiring Manager who just landed a top performer. Perhaps even more satisfying is successfully recruiting a superstar and then seeing them develop a billion-dollar product. Knowing my efforts impact the bottom line keeps me going every day.

In addition to my knowledge base, I actively seek out new technologies and stay up-to-date on industry trends and advancements. I am currently building experience in Designing H.R. Processes, Technical Recruiting, Talent Sourcing, Strategy Development, Recruitment and Selection, Employee onboarding, Payroll Management, HRIS, Employer branding, Learning and development, and other Human Resources functions spanning Tech startups, Consulting, Financial technology space, and N.G.O. sectors.

This has allowed me to stay ahead of the curve and deliver exceptional work to all of my clients.

Education

Apr 2015 - Apr 2019 BSc. Microbiology Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife

Employment

Apr 2022 - Present

Talent Acquisition Manager, Tech Lead - Full-Time

PG Consulting, Lagos, Nigeria

Building relationships with clients.

Sourcing potential candidates on platforms such as LinkedIn and GitHub.

Serving as an ambassador for PG Consulting and representing her in potential candidates' first interactions with the organization.

Performing pre-screening calls to analyze applicants' abilities.

Interviewing candidates using various methods (e.g., structured interviews, technical assessments, and behavioral questions).

Coordinating with Technical team leaders to forecast department goals and hiring needs. Crafting and sending personalized recruiting emails with current job openings to passive candidates.

Keeping up-to-date with new technological trends and products.

Creating a seamless candidate experience through all stages.

Actively engaging and promoting diversity and inclusion in hiring strategies.

Apr 2022 - Dec 2022 Talent Acquisition Specialist, Tech and Non-Tech - Contract HR Stream, Utah, U.S.A

Providing software consulting services to clients of HR Stream.

Utilizing various direct and innovative I.T. sourcing approaches, including social media, internet sourcing, name generation research, and networking, to generate qualified I.T. candidates for different engineering roles.

Implementing technical recruitment strategies that contribute to the enhancement of HR Stream global I.T. hiring processes.

Apr 2020 - March 2022 Talent Acquisition Specialist, Tech - Contract Xapic Technologies, Lagos, Nigeria

Headhunted candidates

Interviewed and assessed prospective applicants and matched them with vacancies at client companies

Screened candidates and drew up shortlists of candidates for clients to interview Organized interviews and selection events

Made arrangements for the advertisement of vacancies

Helped applicants to prepare for interviews Built relationships with clients

Sep 2021 - Mar 2022

Frontend Developer | Technical Recruiter - Full-Time

Pericius Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Bengaluru, India

Pinpointed candidate motivators and used them to recruit quality candidates successfully.

Analyzed job descriptions and communicated with the Hiring Manager (Pericius Technologies Pvt. Ltd) to clarify terms that could be vague; earned job satisfaction rates of 95 percent from candidate/company match as a result of this attention to detail.

Created new features, functionality, and capabilities in the Contract Management System using ReactJS, Ant Design, Material U.I., and Java.

Performed bug fixes and code reviews.

Recommended solutions for a streamlined, user-friendly interface with the design team.

May 2021 - Jun 2021 Frontend Developer - Contract Mezovest, Lagos, Nigeria

Built an online payment gateway that allows businesses to make and receive payments across continents, currencies, preferred payment methods, and platforms.

Oct 2020 - Jan 2021 Software Developer - Contract Royal Crystal Airways, Lagos, Nigeria

Built the Web Application for Royal Crystal Airways and Royal Trip using ReactJS, Redux, jQuery, Vanilla JavaScript, Material-UI, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Stylus, and ES6.

Oversaw the outsourced Mobile Application development for Royal Crystal Airways and Royal Trip.

Jan 2019 - Mar 2020 Frontend Developer - Contract Midra Solutions, Lagos, Nigeria Maintained, optimized, troubleshot, and improved websites.

Created standardized websites and mobile responsive applications using a mobile-first approach and strategy.

Implemented applications and landing pages from concept through deployment. Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments. Built reusable code for future use.

Jan 2017 - Jan 2019 Software Developer (Intern) - Full-time Lagosbuild, Lagos, Nigeria

Standardized website output with a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy.

Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility.

Integrated data from various back-end services and databases.

Skills

ATS Recruitment Software
Boolean search (LinkedIn and Google)
X-ray search - Recruit'em
Leadership
People Management
Employee Onboarding
MS Office suite (Excel, Word, PowerPoint)
Recruitment
Selection
Learning & Development

Vanilla JavaScript ReactJS Ant Design Bootstrap VueJS Material UI

Certificates

Mar 2022

Tech Recruitment Certified Professional - DevSkiller

Jan 2022

ReactJS for Beginners - Simplilearn

Jan 2022

JavaScript for Beginners - Simplilearn

Dec 2021

Getting Started with ReactJS Components - Simplilearn

Apr 2021

Soft Skills Course - Jobberman Nigeria

Mar 2021

Certificate of Language Ability - Emmersion

Mar 2021

HTML/CSS and JavaScript - TestDome

Skills and Competencies

Adept with MS Office suite (Excel, Word, PowerPoint).

Skilled user of office tech tools (ATS, Bamboo, Greenhouse, Workable, Recruitee & Zoho Recruit, Airtable, Notion, Outlook, Slack, Skype, Google Drive, and Google Form).

Outstanding Technical Recruiting, Employer Branding, HR report writing, Talent Sourcing, Organization design, and communication skills.

Excellent leadership, people management, and Employee onboarding skills.

First-rate IT Recruitment, Selection, and Learning & Development skills.

Proven experience in sourcing for regular and just-in-time positions such as emergencies, proposals, and short-term positions.

Experience with using Boolean search strategy to hire talents.

Good conflict management, compensation and benefit, and diversity and inclusion skills.

Good performance management, employee relations, and team management skills.

Selected Accomplishments

Recruited technical talents for European and Global companies like; Remotebase and Robert Half.

Volunteering

Jobs Meet Devs, Lagos, Nigeria